Jabison Rafael de Aguiar Bezerra



Contact

contato@jabsrafael.com.br

+55 (81) 99226-4839

Vila Butantã, São Paulo - SP

🌐 jabsrafael.com.br

Hard Skills

- Software Development
- OT/IT CyberSecurity
- · DevSecOps Engineering
- · Nuclear Engineering
- 3D Printing (FDM + SLA)
- Hardware
- Mechanical Projecting
- Materials Science and Engineering

Soft Skills

- Quick learner
- Multi-tasking
- Proactive
- Able to manage multiple projects simultaneously
- Strong sense of urgency
- Broad knowledge across diverse areas

Technical Skills

- C# Intermediate/Advanced
- Python Intermediate/Advanced
- Golang Intermediate
- Visual Basic Intermediate
- HTML/CSS Intermediate
- SQL Server / PostgreSQL Intermediate
- AutoCAD/SolidWorks/Inventor Intermediate
- IT and OT Cybersecurity
- · Cloud Computing Intermediate

Education Background

- IFPE Recife
 Technical Course in Electronics
 2015-2018
- Universidade Estadual de Campinas UNICAMP Physics Engineering 2020 - 2022
- Universidade de São Paulo USP Nuclear Engineering 2022
- Uniaméricas Descomplica
 Computer Engineering
 2022

About Me

Originally from Recife, Pernambuco, my academic and professional journey is characterized by a diverse and evolving skill set that spans multiple disciplines. My career began with a technical course in electronics, which ignited my passion for technology and led me to explore the automotive industry. This exploration was followed by a deep dive into the realms of Physical Engineering, Nuclear Engineering, and Computer Engineering.

My eclectic background has equipped me with a wide range of skills, from 3D printing and design to programming and cybersecurity. This diversity enables me to quickly identify and efficiently solve problems, a testament to my T-shaped professional profile. I am currently focused on specializing in Cybersecurity within the context of Nuclear Engineering, aiming to bridge the gap between IT and Operational Technology (OT) security. My unique blend of skills and experiences positions me to make significant contributions to the field, especially in addressing the unique challenges of cybersecurity in nuclear facilities.

Professional Experience

PoliRugby Academy - Marketing Director 2022-2023

Key responsibilities:

• Manage and create posts for the social media of the team

IPEN / CNEN-SP - Software Developer 2022-2024

Key responsibilities:

- Spearheaded the design and development of Brazil's radioactive waste characterization software.
- Defined use cases and streamlined processes for efficient waste management.
- Implemented innovative solutions to enhance software functionality and user experience.

Capim | Tech Intern 2023-2024

Key responsibilities:

- Development of the data import feature
- Established the support division, serving as the primary point for resolving bugs and issues, overseeing bug resolution and collaborated with development teams to address root causes of issues.
- Contributed to the development and optimization of cloud infrastructure, enhancing scalability and security
- Assisted in deploying and managing cloud services, ensuring efficient operation and cost-effectiveness.

Achievements

2022-2024	Developed a significant software for the characterization of waste from Brazilian Nuclear Power Plants.
2022	Winner of Rosatom - MEPhl Nuclear Engineering HackAtom
2023	Developed the data import feature, which proved to be a game changer that contributed to clients adopting the platform.
2023	Winner of HP & USP Hackathon
2023-2024	Reduced the company's cloud-based credit engine costs by 80%.